片名: 尼罗河宝石
这一天非比寻常
It was a day like no other.
也是我自小梦想的一天
It was a day I had always dreamed of.
我永生难忘的日子
A day I would never forget.
你愿意娶这位女士 以真心待她 直到永远吗
Will you marry this woman and take her to your heart, forever devoted and forever young?
我愿意!
I will.
你愿意嫁给这位男士 以真心待他
And will you marry this man and take him to your heart,
直到永远吗
forever devoted and forever young?
我愿意!
I will.
请你为她戴上戒指
Would you now place the ring on her finger?
我谨此宣布
I now declare...
半路杀出了程咬金
What a shame we had uninvited guests.
看来今天大有收获了
I'll have what I came for this day!
杰克很客气地请他们走
Jack politely asked him to leave.
有种来吧 混蛋
Kiss steel, bastard!
杰克
Jack!
你别怕 我马上来
Hold tight! I'm coming!
他战志高昂 但态度却不失绅士
His temper flared, but he fought like a gentleman.
杰克
Jack.
Jack!
我唯一的真爱 英勇地作战 但这还不够
My one true love had fought bravely, but it wasn't enough.
船上只能再容纳一个人
There was only room for one more.
不是他就是我
It was either my love or myself.
- 你搭吧 爱人 - 不行 他们别想得到你
- You take it, my love. - Never! Those maggots will not have you.
他们不会得到我太久
They will not have me for long.
我得了肺痨 不出一年就要死了
I have consumption and will be dead before the year is out.
你带着肺痨嫁我 干嘛不告诉我?
You were gonna marry me with consumption? Why didn't you tell me?
我不想扫你的兴
I didn't want to spoil things.
- 走吧 - 不要
- Go. - No!
留着青山在不怕没柴烧
Live to fight another day.
只要你快乐就好
Whatever makes you happy.
杰克永远关心我的幸福
With Jack, my happiness always came first.
我又单独面对命运了
I faced my fate alone.
10个变20个 20个变40个
The 10 turned to 20, the 20 to 40.
这会是我自由 和救赎的终结吗? 我的...
Could this be the end of my freedom, my salvation, my...
小美人
Hey, gorgeous!
琼妮
Hiya, Joanie!
怎么了?
What happened?
这会是我自由 和救赎的终结吗?
"Was this the end of my freedom, my salvation?"
我的事业...
My career?
美好的一天 是吧? 小美人
Gorgeous day. Huh, gorgeous?
蔚蓝的天空
We got blue skies,
温暖的海水 冰凉的啤酒
nice warm water and a cold beer.
甜心 啤酒还有存货吗?
Honey, did you get any more Buds?
没有了 我没空上岸 替你买啤酒
No, I just didn't have time today to ravage the Riviera for your beer.
- 今天够呛的了? - 没错 你说的对
- Tough day, huh? - Yeah, you could say it was tough.
不过我这个人越累越行
But then when the going gets tough, the tough...
其实强有什么用?
I don't know what the tough do.
海盗做什么 其他人又做什么一概不知
I don't know what the pirates do, or what anybody does.
- 杰克... - 我了解 甜心 我了解的
- Jack... - Oh, honey. I know, baby. I know.
你看那头 看见了什么?
Look out there. What do you see?
- 布鲁明迪尔? - 不是的
- Bloomingdale's? - No.
希腊
Greece.
利斯伯 维根 克里斯 我们都要去
Yeah. Mykonos, Lesbos, ouzo, olive oil. Honey, we're going.
等一下 你不是说要回纽约的?
Wait. I thought you said that we were going back to New York for a while.
那当然 等夏天一结束 咱们就去
Absolutely. When the summer's over we're going.
杰克 我们在船上待半年了 我只休短假呀
Oh, Jack, we've been on this boat half a year now. I need shore leave.
我答应葛洛莉3个月前 就写完那本书的 可是我没有
I promised Gloria I'd finish that book three months ago, and I can't.
不知道接下来会如何
I don't know what happens next.
你不是说要陪我环游世界的?
I thought you wanted to sail around the world with me.
没错呀 可是...不是这个星期
Well, I do, but not all of it this week.
杰克 这太乱了
I mean, Jack, this is just becoming a blur.
异国风情的港口 热闹的派对和灿烂的日落
Exotic ports and great parties and spectacular sunsets...
这些不够
It's not enough.
不够?
It's not enough?!
你好像是一个拥有一切 却突然什么都不要的人
You sound like someone who's got what they wanted and now don't want what they got.
- 我要做一些正经的事 - 得了吧你
- I wanna do something serious. - Serious? Come on!
杰克 一个女人 能承受多少浪漫
How much romance can one woman take?
琼妮怀德
Joan Wilder?
你的读者送的
From your most devoted friend.
谢谢你
Thank you.
期待已久的一刻就在今天下午 这是干什么?
"This afternoon we shall meet... awaiting the moment." What's this afternoon?
- 一定是来参加欢迎会的 - 下星期二才举行的
- Must be somebody coming to the reception. - That's not till next Tuesday.
今天就是呀 杰克
This is "next Tuesday", Jack.
- 你不是说要叫车子的 - 我不知道今天周二 对不起
- Jack, you said you were getting a car. - If I knew it was Tuesday, I would've. Sorry.
无所谓
That's all right.
咱们到城里去逛逛如何?
Whaddaya say we spin that roulette wheel while we're there?
太好了
Sounds great.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
杰克
Jack.
- 嗯? - 这会还不能走
- Yeah? - She can't leave now.
- 为什么? - 这是什么话?
- Why not? - What do you mean, "Why not?"
- 天啊 - 我是你最忠实的粉丝
- Oh, my God. - I'm your biggest fan!
- 我读过你所有的书 - 谢谢
- I read all your books. - Thank you.
很高兴见到你
I'm so happy to see you.
- 这位是我的出版商 葛洛莉哈恩 - 噢 出版商
- This is my publisher. Gloria Horne. - Oh, your publisher.
- 这位是... - 你是怀德先生啰?
- And this is... - You are Mr Wilder?
不对 我姓柯顿
No, I'm Mr Colton. Jack Colton.
你在哪高就呀
What do you do, Mr Colton?
经营赌场的
Casino work.
对 我下去一会 失陪 失陪一下
Yeah. I think I'll go downstairs and punch in. Excuse me, excuse me.
- 但... - 马上回来
- But... - I'll be back!
来喝一杯吧
God, I've got to have a drink!
这种场合不适合杰克
Literary functions are not Jack's speed.
他喜欢的作家 是打蝴蝶结的那种
I mean, his favourite author is the man who wrote "Pull Tab to Open".
- 我是他最喜欢的作家 - 你的意思是我多管闲事
- I am his favourite author. - You saying it's none of my business?
我老实告诉你吧 杰克不做兴结婚
Let me tell you, Jack is not the marrying kind.
我为你担心呐 你连借书都按期归还
I am worried. You're the girl who never gets a book back late to the library.
现在却拖了3个月 你是怎么搞的?
You are three months past your deadline. What gives? Un scotch, double.
我定不下心来 浪漫对我已不再真实了
My heart just isn't in it. Romance just doesn't seem real to me any more.
真实? 没人叫你写真 而是写日落航海呀
Real? You don't write "real". You write about people that sail off into the sunset.
- 天亮出太阳时怎么说 - 没有天亮 所以叫浪漫呀
- And the next day when the sun comes up? - There is no next day in romance.
别把生活和浪漫小说混为一谈
Stop confusing real life with a romantic novel.
- 琼妮 快完成吧 - 我没办法
- Joanie, just finish it. - I can't.
写完17本小说 我已经江郎才尽了
After 17 books, I don't know how it ends any more.
那就听我的说法吧
Then permit me to tell you.
没有所谓的结局
It doesn't end.
与我共游尼罗河 你将有崭新的开始
It only begins anew when you journey down the Nile with me.
- 你没找错对象吧? - 找错了
- Have you got the right woman? - No.
在下是奥马哈里法 千里迢迢寻你千百度
My name is Omar Khalifa and I have travelled 1,000 miles to tell you I need you.
- 花是你送的? - 鲜花美人相得益彰
- You sent me the flowers. - They pale by your beauty.
妈妈呀
Oh, Mary!
- 我看过你的报导 - 没错 我知道 是时代杂志
- I read about you. - Yes, I know. Time magazine.
不过西方记者 并不能了解我的远见
Well, I'm afraid the Western press cannot understand the spirit of my vision.
你是作家 你会了解我
You are a writer. You can understand.
也只有你有资格为我着书立传
So, Joan Wilder, you must come and write my story.
我写只浪漫小说
I only write romance novels.
对 手头上这本都还没完成呐
Yes. And you haven't finished the one you're working on right now.
你有说故事的才华 在罪恶的俗世中创造英雄
You are a gifted storyteller. You create heroes in a world of cynics.
与我同游尼罗河吧 我让你重新咀嚼历史
Journey down the Nile with me and I'll give you a chance to record history.
- 今天就启程 - 琼妮
- Come. We must leave today. - Joanie!
再过5天我就要当皇帝了 你却凭白得到独家新闻
In just four nights I will become Emperor, and you will have the exclusive story.
- 尼罗河有皇帝? - 现在有了
- They have emperors on the Nile? - They do now.
糟了
Oh, shit.
庆祝什么?
So now what are we celebrating?
- 尼罗河 - 尼罗河呀
- The Nile! - Oh, the Nile.
有人邀请我们去非洲
We've been invited to Africa.
杰克柯顿 奥马哈里法
Jack Colton, Omar Khalifa.
你好
How do you do?
他要我写他的传记 正是我梦寐以求的事
He's asked me - me - to write his story. It's just what I've always wanted to do!
并让她的作品受到应有的注目
And now Joan's work will receive the serious attention that it deserves.
保证是她有生最大的成就
And this will be her biggest accomplishment:
人格保证
My biography.
尼罗河有什么吸引人 非这时候去不可?
What's so important there that you have to write the book now?
- 哈里法先生他... - 请叫奥马好了
- Mr Khalifa has... - Omar, please.
奥马身负团结尼罗河各部落的大任
Omar has been chosen to unite the tribes of the Nile
终止该区流血内战
and end the strife that has bloodied his land.
他将继承失踪先皇的重责大任
He will carry on the work of the missing Great Redeemer.
- 你的记性出奇的好 - 才20分钟你就耳熟能详了?
- You have listened very well. - You got all that in 20 minutes?
即然你是怀德小姐的好友 欢迎同行
As a friend of Miss Wilder's, you are welcome to be my guest also.
- 谢谢 - 荣幸之至
- Thank you. - My pleasure.
可以谈一下吗?
Could I talk to you for a minute, please?
你不要去纽约的?
I thought you wanted to go to New York.
- 此一时彼一时呀 - 这么善变?
- That's all changed. - That fast?
杰克 写自传不比寻常
But to write a biography - it's something important, something real.
- 对我意义重大呀 - 你不嫌得意忘形了吗?
- This is what I've been looking for. - Isn't it a little bit over your head?
这是难得的机会
I think it's a great chance.
这么说你心意已决了?
So you got your heart set on it?
我也没话说了
Mine's set on Greece.
打算几时走?
So when are you gonna leave?
今晚...他有私人客机
Tonight. He has a private jet and...
他有私人客机呀?
Oh, he's got a private jet.
- 相处的快乐就不当一回事了? - 杰克 别这样嘛
- Oh, what the hell. We had a good run. - Oh, Jack, come on.
顶多4 5个礼拜罢了
This is just five or four weeks of research.
你说的也对 是需要分开一阵子
Maybe you're right. Maybe we need a break.
最近老是不顺
It's been kind of tough lately.
对呀 你不是说越苦你越强的
Yeah. When the going gets tough, the tough go to Greece.
- 等我的信 - 寄到哪呀?
- Well, I'll write you. - Where?
可不是...
Yeah.
寄哪呀?
Where?
我再下去试试赌轮吧
I think I'll go down and give that roulette wheel one more chance.
你好好保重
You take care of yourself.
别惹麻烦哟
And you stay out of trouble.
替我照顾她好吗?
Look out for her, will ya?
这么说你或许会宽心 她为更高的理想而与你小别
I can offer you this comfort: She leaves you for a higher purpose.
是啊
Yeah.
自由迦哇拉!
Free Al-Jawhara!
不用怕 我是有先见的人 免不了树敌
Don't be frightened. You know, a man of vision has many enemies.
不过我的八字硬 你瞧
And my destiny is to outsmart them. You see?
喜欢吧
Like it?
没事!
It's OK.
只剩下咱俩独守寂寞了
Well, sweetheart, I guess it's just you and me.
他娘的 我一生中最美好的时刻
Goddamn it, she was the best time I ever had.
别自怜了 小癟蛋 有我陪着你
Don't cry, scumbag! I'll keep you company.
老混球 我爱你 太久不见了...
Cartagena, Colombia! Long time no... Oh, shit.
- 说呀 你解释一下 安抚我 - 别冲动 别冲动
- Go ahead. Gimme a reason. Make my year! - Hey, go easy with the gun.
我想念你
I missed you.
半年下来天天惦着你
You're all I thought about for six months.
被丢进牢里 忍受那些臭虫和传染病
They threw me in a jail filled with rejects from the communicable disease ward.
挤满了下三滥 人渣 黄 毒 杀 抢的全齐了
Every wacko, drippy, open-sored lowlife was in that joint!
要老子研究昆虫
All wanting to be my proctologist.
还有老鼠 老鼠呀 咬得我满身伤口
And rats! I'm full of rat bites.
一连十个礼拜 打这么长的狂犬病针 我却一心惦着你 柯顿 一心想你
Ten weeks of rabies shots this long and all I thought of was you, Colton. Just you!
我何等荣幸 对不起 让你受苦了
Well, I'm flattered, pal. And I'm sorry you had such a tough time.
- 给你一百块怎么样? - 一百块?
- How about 100 bucks? - 100 bucks?
老子一枪送你去见阎王 少打屁 你弄哪去啦?
I'll give you a one-way ticket to Harp Land! What'd you do with it?
- 你胡扯什么? - 宝石呀 白痴 老子毙了你
- What are you talking about? - The stone, moron! I'm cocked!
- 听我说 有话好商量成不成 - 商量个屁 你可知道老子得了虐疾?
- Let's talk about this like gentlemen. - Gentlemen! Did I tell you I got malaria?
我一发抖的时候...你可知道会有什么后果吗
Every time I shake, I shake like this. Know what happens if I shake my trigger finger?
我就有股冲动想干人 你知道是什么下场吗?
And I feel an attack coming on! Know what happens if that happens?
就是狗运先生的末日 狗运先生...
It's the end of Mr Lucky. That's the end of...
我的妈呀
Holy shit!
天老爷呀 下一次就没这么好运了
Quiet! Next time you'll not be so lucky.
- 我是塔拉克 跟我一起走 - 你是什么人?
- I am Tarak. You must come with me now. - What the hell are you?
- 在乔哈拉差点偷咱们宝石的人 - 宝石?
- Omar steal our jewel. Al-Jawhara. - Jewel?
你和那个女的都被邀过 你能进入奥马的皇宫 我的人不能
You were invited with the woman. You can get into Omar's palace. My people cannot.
- 什么人? 我根本不认识你 - 你得帮我找宝石
- What people? What are you talking about? - You must help me find the Jewel.
- 什么宝石? - 尼罗河宝石
- What jewel? - The Jewel of the Nile.
- 最珍贵的宝石 - 噢 那颗宝石
- Our most priceless jewel. - Oh, that jewel.
奥马偷了我们的宝石 他是个坏胚子
Omar has stolen my people's jewel. Omar is a very bad man.
那个人渣 我唾他口水
Oh, that scum! I spit on him!
杰克兄弟 帮帮这个好人拿回宝石
Jack, buddy, let's help this nice man get his jewel back.
- 对 - 我不知道你什么来历 什么身份
- Yes. - Look, I don't know where you're from,
我今晚就搭船离开
but I'm sailing my boat tonight.
不行 现在就帮我找宝石 免得奥马滥杀无辜
No, you must come to help find the Jewel now before Omar kill many people.
只要宝石在他手上一天 谁也治不了他
As long as Omar have the Jewel, nothing can stop him.
我可要上船了 你们随便吧
Look, I'm going on the boat. You guys can do what you want.
船炸了
The boat blew up!
My boat blew up.
船炸了
The boat blew up!
爱琳是完蛋了
Everything's gone.
你是黑暗王子不成? 你没朋友吗?
Who are you? The Prince of Darkness? Don't you got any friends?
是奥马搞出来的
This is the work of Omar.
- 奥马居然炸了我的船 - 琼妮正身处危险之中
- Omar blew up my boat, huh? - Your woman is in danger, too.
我带你去见他
I will take you to him.
- 我也一道去 - 你休想
- I'm coming, too. - The hell you are!
你欠我的情
Look, you owe me, Colton.
不管你去哪 都别想把我甩了
So wherever you're going, I'm going.
咱们去哪?
Where we going?
非洲
Africa.
- 认得出我的家乡吗? - 我写过
- Do you recognise my home? - I wrote this!
没错 国王重返故土 我设计好一套一样的制服
Yes! In The Return of the King. I had the same uniforms designed.
- 全是你的? - 是国家和百姓的
- Is all this yours? - It belongs to the country. To my people.
何必急着拍照?
Why point out the negative?
再过四天就满月
In three nights in Kadir the moon will be full,
所有部落将团结推举我 这会拍的都无足轻重了
and all my people will unite behind me in peace and none of this will be necessary.
- 我带你参观我的住处 - 谢谢
- Now let me show you my humble house. - Thank you.
我受了神赐 百姓爱戴我
I'm really blessed. My people love me.
没错 他们都很热情
Well, yes. They seem very... enthusiastic.
这一张拍的好 小男孩手握我的照片
Oh, this is a good shot for you - the little boy holding up my picture.
太棒了
Oh, yeah, that's wonderful.
这是我的寒舍
My humble house.
原谅我 我们是穷困的民族
You must forgive us. We are a poor people.
需要什么 他们都会送来
Everything you need, they will bring you.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
敝国只有生人才说谢谢 亲朋好友则不必客套
Here only strangers say thank you. Family and friends have no need.
是什么?
What was that?
猫呀 请吧
Cats. Come.
我也养猫
I have a cat.
敬礼
Salute.
希望你不嫌弃
I hope this is satisfactory.
是的 太好了 好得很
Oh, yes, this is OK. Fine.
你安心在这完成大作吧
Here you'll write your masterpiece.
先请教几个问题
Ah, I have a few questions...
这么快就忙正事了 好
I see the writer is already at work. Good.
新世界任你探索
Explore your new world.
进出别太拘束 去看所有的一切
Feel free to go anywhere and see anything.
多找些人聊聊
Talk to anyone.
很高兴你光临 我们联手共创历史
I'm glad you're here, Joan. Together we'll make history.
简直像鱼桶
It's like a fishbowl!
这种地方为什么这么热 你倒说说看
Why do these Third World cesspools always gotta be so hot, will you tell me that?
你往哪去呀?
Hey, where the hell you going?
我的妈呀
Holy shit!
柯顿 看情形 好戏已开锣了
Well, Colton, looks like we've hitched our wagon to a star.
停呀
Stop that! Stop it!
对不起
Excuse me?
这是什么意思?
What does this mean?
乔哈拉
Eid lana Al-Jawhara.
乔哈拉?
Al-Jawhara?
- 你会说英语吗? - 还我宝石
- Do you speak English? - "Give back the Jewel."
- 还我宝石? - 对 就乔哈拉的意思
- Give back the jewel? - Yeah. Eid lana Al-Jawhara.
你不能这样子 我是专业摄影师
You can't do that! I'm a professional.
你等着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
你不告诉我这是怎么回事
If you don't tell me what the hell is going on here,
- 我就搭第一班飞机回纽约 - 不可能的事
- I'll be on the first plane back to New York. - It's impossible.
咱们明天回卡地亚 你非去不可 会成为你书中最重要的一部份
Tomorrow we journey to Kadir. You must be there. It will be your most important chapter.
- 你这样隐瞒着 我不能写书呀 - 隐瞒什么呀?
- I can't write if you keep secrets from me. - What secrets?
乔哈拉
Al-Jawhara.
是什么宝石?
What is the Jewel?
宝石是传奇
The Jewel is a legend.
我是持有人
I am real.
别被这种事分心 琼妮怀德
Do not be distracted from your mission, Joan Wilder.
把这当自己的家
Make yourself comfortable.
你陪着我直到 等那本书完成为止
You stay with me until our book is done.
你不能硬留我
You can't keep me here!
走呀 这是你的自由
Go. You are free to leave.
只有大傻瓜才会 单枪匹马横越沙漠
Only the worst kind of fool would attempt our desert alone.
这鬼骆驼弄得我 老屁股都快裂了 气死人了
I gotta get off this camel. It's breaking my ass! Colton!
- 你必须坚持和接受它 - 我不能
- You gotta hang on and take it. - I can't.
- 这么癫人 - 妈的
- The camp's coming up. - Shit!
欢迎呀 各位朋友
You are welcome!
这儿有吃的 也有喝的
We have food! We have drink!
有洗手间吗?
You got a toilet?
宝石有多大呀
So how big is this jewel?
乔哈拉有多大吗?
How big is Al-Jawhara?
非常大 非常非常大
Very, very big. Very big. Very, very big.
大得不得了
Very big.
比这个橘子还大吗?
It's as big as this orange?
乔哈拉跟橘子比?
Compare with Al-Jawhara?
- 是比橘子大 - 宝石是百姓的心
- It's as big as an orange. - The Jewel is the heart of our people.
奥马偷走了百姓的心
Omar steals the heart of our people.
- 奥马是个贼 - 奥马是个大坏蛋
- Omar is thief. - Omar is very bad man.
他偷宝石以前 一切都好好的
Before Omar steal Jewel, everything good.
这会儿什么都变了样
Now everything is shit!
你们帮我们找回宝石 我们就大大地赏你们
You help us find the Jewel, and we give you great reward.
不过嘛 要是敢耍我们 就别想活着走
But if you lie to us, you die.
开始跳舞了
But now we dance!
瞧瞧这批人吧
Look at these guys, Colton.
饿得跟狼一样
No sheep is safe tonight.
咱们对分 柯顿 一人一半
We split it right down the middle, Colton. 50-50.
你胡说什么?
What are you talking about?
别跟我装傻 伙计
Don't play stupid with me, partner.
宝石呀
The Jewel.
更别妄想耍我花枪
And don't you even think of messing with me.
怎么着? 心碎了是吧? 没出息的
Oh, what's that I hear? A heart breaking? You sap!
还是把心思放在生意上吧
Keep your mind on business.
别为了一个无情的臭娘们 丢了老命
You'll wind up getting yourself killed over some broad who dumped you.
宝石
Jewels!
妈妈咪呀
Oh, Omar!
小心着点
I want you lot to be careful!
箱上写着"小心易碎"呀
See that word "Fragile" on the side? It means don't drop... Why don't you listen?
搞什么鬼? 你不爱它 它也不会爱你
I might love your country, your culture, and even your people! That means I love you!
再摔一次 老子一脚踢死你
But you drop one more of my boxes, and I'll smash your bloody face in!
你告诉奥马 他要的举世精品到了
You tell Omar, right - Omar - that his special-effects wizard has arrived!
来吧
Come on, then.
作战计划 我的天呀 他搞什么阴谋
War plans? Oh, my God! What is he up to?
等着我弄上时代杂志吧
Wait till Time magazine sees this.
你这个混帐 烧到我的手啦
You bastard! You burnt my hand!
我没说不会烧 我只说不会痛的 没有起泡 没起泡呀
I didn't say it wouldn't burn. I said it wouldn't hurt! There's no blistering.
- 我在台上表演几百遍了 - 这可不是低俗的非洲特技
- I've done it hundreds of times on stage. - This is not a cheap theatrical stunt!
- 这是奇迹 要让我的百姓相信才行 - 奥马 相信我吧 你相信我呀
- It's a miracle! My people have to believe it! - Omar, trust me. Trust what I've got to say.
我既能乞丐成为摇滚歌星 自然是有两下子了
Look, if I can make gods out of rock'n'roll stars, imagine what I can do for you.
你大概还没搞懂 我可不是摇滚歌星
For your information, I am not a rock'n'roll star!
一定要百姓相信 我的威力和宝石一样
The people must believe I have the same powers as the Jewel.
来吧 我现在就要见他
Come! I want to see him now.
要不是为了宝石 百姓早就归顺于我了
If it weren't for the Jewel, I'd have led my people to power long ago.
我要怎么说服他们 宝石并没什么神奇
Westerners understand nothing. The Jewel represents the spiritual world of my people.
除非我能说服他们 我才是他们的精神导师 他们是不会跟我作战的
Unless I convince them I am their spiritual leader, they will never follow me into battle.
所以才把你找了来
That is why you are here.
- 告诉我是怎么变的 - 我用的不是魔术 是奇迹
- Tell me how it's done, magician. - It's not magic trick. It's miracle.
老子没耐心听你扯了
I am losing patience with you.
不过你不能杀我 你也一样迷信这一套
But you cannot kill me. Even you are superstitious.
乔哈拉长存不朽
Al-Jawhara lives.
这一切都不重要了
Two nights from now it will not matter.
你滚
Leave.
噢 不
Oh, no.
是个女人?
A woman?
- 可真料不到呀 - 我得离开这
- Most unexpected. - I gotta get outta here.
我要制止奥马
I gotta stop Omar.
你带了部队来吗?
Did you bring an army?
- 没有哇 我是琼妮怀德 - 你是琼妮怀德? 我是乔哈拉
- No. I'm just Joan Wilder. - Just-Joan Wilder, I'm Al-Jawhara.
你是乔哈拉?
Al-Jawhara?
尼罗河宝石呀
The Jewel of the Nile.
别唬我...
I don't understand.
- 你就是宝石? - 对 目前是
- You are the Jewel?! - Yes. For the moment.
再过3天 奥马在卡迪亚自封皇帝
In two nights at the holy city of Kadir Omar will proclaim himself Emperor.
如果我不出面制止 他就会疯狂地攻打北非
Without me to oppose him, he'll march across North Africa like a madman.
不过世人将视我为 百姓的救主
But the world will see me as the saviour of my people.
你错了 世人不会相信你 我去过你的办公室 看过你的远见
No, it won't. The world won't believe you. I've been in your office and seen your vision.
- 我要抖出你的内幕 - 内幕?
- I'll write the truth about you. - The truth?
我要报内幕 早请60分钟小组了
If I wanted the truth, I would have hired 60 Minutes.
你又懂些什么 你只会幻想罢了
What do you know about truth? You fantasise everything.
你以为我干嘛带你来这? 你乖乖地待着 我说什么你就写什么
Why do you think I brought you here? You stay here and write what I tell you to write!
- 你以为没人知道我在这? - 杰克知道 我居然忘了告诉你
- You think no one knows I'm here? - Oh, yes, Jack! I forgot to tell you.
杰克死了
Jack is dead.
你别扯了 杰克不会不告诉我就死掉
Don't be ridiculous. Jack would never die without telling me.
可惜他是死了
Nevertheless, he is dead.
你脸色仓白呀 怀德小姐 我请私人医生来看你
You look pale, Miss Wilder. I'll send you my personal physician.
不可能的
It can't be true.
那个杰克... 他是你朋友?
This Jack... He is friend for you?
是的
Yes.
他是我最好的朋友
He is my best friend.
怎么了? 我什么都没看到
What? I don't see shit!
我们得在这等
We must stop here.
这会儿进奥马的城里 太危险了
It is dangerous for Sufis to enter Omar's city.
等等 这家伙 有一度想杀了我
Now, wait. He's already tried to kill me once.
很好
Good.
你是奥马的贵宾
You are guest of Omar.
替我们找宝石吧 接受自己的命运吧
Find for us the Jewel. Accept your destiny.
命运个屁
Destiny, my ass! Excuse me.
跟这批神经病搞在一起 就是这种下场
When you hook up with jujubes, see what happens.
你只管好好跟着我 包你没事
Just take your lead from me, and we'll be fine.
- 你打算大摇大摆地进城吗 - 我要让你骑骆驼 癫死你
- We gonna walk through the centre of town? - I'm gonna put you up a camel's ass.
搞不好我正喜欢呢
I might like it.
- 你干什么呀 - 我有一本书里...
- What are you doing? - In one of my books,
描写一个密道
Angelina's Savage Secret,
主角用指甲锉来撬窗子
she used her nailfile to cut the mortar away from the window box.
需要多少时间呐?
How long did this take?
两页
Two pages.
关人的不是铁栅 而是沙漠
But... it's not the bars that make the prison. It is the desert.
所以我得漏夜赶路 我不在乎 我得阻止奥马
So I'll travel at night. I don't care. I have to stop Omar.
我一定要出去 把真相揭发出来
I gotta get out to write the truth about him.
赶去卡迪亚
I have to get to Kadir.
等一下 你才该去卡迪亚的
Wait a minute. You are the one that has to get to Kadir.
只有你才能阻止他 你一定要跟我走
You are the only one that can stop Omar. You have to go with me!
说不定你就是贵人
Maybe you are the one.
我接受
I accept.
我们是患难之交 琼妮怀德
We are sworn, Just-Joan.
- 对 叫琼妮就好 - 好 就这么叫
- Right. But it's just Joan. - Right. Just-Joan.
- 我得把窗户撬开 - 我来吧
- Right. We just have to get out this window. - Please.
- 魔术? - 是念力
- Magic! - Dry rot.
我敢说只要5 6块 就能租间好套房
I bet you could pick up a swell three-bedroom town house here for about five or six dollars.
各位好 在下是柯顿
Hi. My name is Colton.
是奥马请来的 我来见琼妮怀德
I've been invited by your Omar. I'm here to see Joan Wilder.
拉西 琼妮怀德在不在?
Rachid, is Joan Wilder still here?
拉西 你好 幸会
Hey, Rachid! How are you? Good to see you again.
她不想见你
Joan Wilder does not want to see you.
拉西 你还没弄明白呀
Well, now, Rachid, I don't think you understand.
我们来这办正事的 他是美国大使佛托西先生
We're here on official business. This is Mr... Fatush from the US Embassy.
他有重要的事跟你们谈
He's got something very important to talk to all you guys about.
我们不想制造国际事件
Look, we don't want to create an international incident here.
毕竟她是美国公民
I mean, after all, she is an American citizen.
你只要让我们见她一面 保证不牵涉公文 绝对不张扬出去 一切放心
If you'll just let us see her, no paperwork. Mum's the word. Everything...
拉哥
Largo.
各位兄弟 别伤了和气 改天再聊吧
Guys, no sweat, OK? We'll catch you next time we're in town.
- 别冲动 - 跟她问声好
- Take it easy. - Say hello to her for us.
坐过牢的都懂得出大门时 不说再见的
You know what they say: Once they've had a holy man, they never go back.
- 快一点呀 琼妮 - 你当真知道方向吗?
- Quickly, Just-Joan! - Are you sure you know where you're going?
我听说过他们潜逃进水里 数小时不用空气
Those guys can go for hours without coming up for air.
别啰嗦了 好吧 一定还有别的门路
Ease up, will ya? All right, there's gotta be another way in here.
真巴不得那末日博士 再耍一招 咱们装扮成小丑
I can't wait for another smooth move. How about us at the back door in pussycat suits?
- 等他们出来倒牛奶时... - 干脆都交给你吧
- When they come with the milk... - How about you takin' it in the ear!?
你听着 老弟 要不是有了我 你早完了
Look, if it wasn't for me, you wouldn't be on to this.
真后悔那天没一枪干掉你
Subsequently I should shoot you the first chance I get!
杰克
Jack!
你还没死呀
You're alive!
想甩我也用不着来这一套
Kinda goin' outta your way to duck me!
你这个混蛋
You bastard!
杰克 我还以为 再也见不到你了
Oh, Jack! I thought I'd never see you again.
奥马说你死了 我居然相信 我不想再有那种感觉了
They told me you were dead. I never wanna feel that way again.
这是你道歉的方式吗?
Does this mean you apologise?
我总觉得又回到小学时代了 这算什么? 阿西和阿花吗?
I feel like I'm back in eighth grade. Is this The Young and the Stupid?
- 他怎么会来这儿的? - 你别想打发我 我也有一份的
- What the hell is he doing here? - Don't get cagey with me. I'm on to it.
用不着在我面前 一搭一唱地演戏
I know how you two operate.
就算没有你们 我还是进得去
I'll get in there with or without you dinks!
各位 别这么小题大做 我只是和老情人打声招呼
Hey, look, guys! Lighten up! I'm only saying hello to an old girlfriend here!
- 琼妮 快点走吧 - 等一下 他是什么人?
- Just-Joan, we need to go! - Wait a minute, who's this guy?
- 朋友 - 你交了朋友?
- He's a friend. - You made friends in there?
- 咱们快走 快 - 等一下 他也一起走
- OK. Let's go, come on! - Wait. He's coming with us.
你别再搞我了 我横越大半个非洲来救你
Don't start with me! I've come halfway across Africa to rescue you.
救我? 我一个人好端端地
Rescue me? I was doing fine without you.
- 我是向导 我能帮忙 - 我不要向导 我要的是奇迹
- I am guide. I can help. - I don't need a guide. I need a miracle!
杰克 他跟我们一道
Jack, he's coming with us.
好吧 只要能活着出去 再宰了你也不迟
All right. But if we get out of this alive, I'm gonna kill you.
快走
Let's go.
- 你是什么人? - 过路的 想问个路
- Who are you? - Is this where Al Jolson's buried?
- 你是什么人? - 别惹毛了我 老弟
- Who the hell are you? - Don't provoke me, pal!
我今天够苦了 这儿又热 连阴凉地都有120度
I had a tough day. You know how hot it is here? It's 120?in the shade.
等我到了温柏格 叫你死得很难看
I'm like this with Weinberger. We'll be all over you!
快进去
Get in.
让我进去
Let me in!
老天爷 这么快就上秀了
Holy shit and shove me in it.
不要 爬墙进去
Oh, no. Over the wall!
借光 借个光
Excuse me. Excuse me.
快
Come on!
不要 不要...
No! No!
好吧 你乖乖给我起飞
OK, flyboy, your estimated time of departure is now!
- 你干什么呀? - 我没干什么呀
- What are you doing? - I'm not doing anything!
- 快停下来呀 - 好 我试试看
- Well, do something! - All right. I'm trying!
看来要演太空侵略者了
I mean, this isn't Space Invaders!
- 杰克 墙呀 - 糟啦
- Jack, the wall! - Oh, no!
- 不愧是太空侵略者 - 你成功了 杰克
- It is Space Invaders! - That'll show 'em!
好呀 上来吧
All right, yeah!
完了
Oh, shit!
快离开吧
Let's get outta here!
这一关不容易哟
This is gonna be tight!
我有生第一次坐飞机
This is my first time in airplane.
这玩意怎么停?
How do you stop this thing?
抱歉
Sorry!
- 你知道方向吗? - 你饶了我吧
- Do you know where you're going? - Give me a break!
射击
Fire.
乔哈拉
Al-Jawhara.
- 你朋友把宝石偷走了 - 什么?
- Your friend steal the Jewel. - What?
- 你骗我 - 没有
- You! You are liar to me! - No!
我会找你算帐 你死定了
I come back and you're dead!
走吧
Go.
混帐东西 别想欺负我
You thieving bastard! You ain't stiffin' me again!
老子抓你喂蛆 等着瞧
I promise ya. I'll feed ya to the maggots! I'll get...
乔哈拉
Al-Jawhara.
停车 停车
Stop! Stop!
要命 没子弹了
Great! We're out of quarters.
试试那一个
Well, try that one there.
怎么办呢?
Now what?
该死
Damn it!
好
Yes!
初试身手算不赖的
Hey, that's not bad for your first time.
快去抓呀 快走 咱们去抓
Come on, we'll get him. We'll get him.
柯顿 你插翅难飞了
Colton, you ain't gettin' away.
喇叭在哪?
Where the hell's the horn?
离开呀 别挡路
Get outta here! Get out of the way!
是沙暴
Sandstorm.
不要
Stop!
你想干什么?
What are you gonna do?
不是救星就阎王 坐稳
Either save us or kill us. Hang on!
- 你死定了 - 别砍我头
- Now you are dead. - No! Don't cut off my head!
- 你偷了我们的宝石 - 不是我 是那个癟三 他专门耍我
- You stole our jewel. - It was the mook! He's always screwin' me.
我对天发誓 我没见过宝石
I swear to God on my eyes I never seen that jewel!
等等 等等
No, wait, wait!
你们用得着我 我能帮你们找到
You need me. I can help you find him.
- 你是他朋友 - 不是 朋友这种字别乱用
- You are his friend. - No! No friend. Stop saying that.
是朋友就不会出卖你
Friends don't stab each other in the back.
听我说 咱们联合阵线 找到他 狠狠整他
Come on. Look, we'll team up. We'll find him, we'll get him good.
他明白我是挡不住的 柯顿这个人没前途
He knows that I will not be denied! Colton's future is bleak!
他前途无亮
Very bleak!
知道这是哪儿吗?
Any idea where we are?
依我估计呀 再朝东走一段就到边界了
The best I can figure out is that we head due east. We should make it to the border.
- 卡迪亚是那个方向吗? - 不对 卡迪亚在西边过了山
- Well... is that the way to Kadir? - La. Kadir is in the west, over that mountain.
祝你好运了 兄弟 琼妮 咱们走吧
Well, the best of luck to you, pal. Joan, let's get going.
杰克 我们得送他去卡迪亚
Jack, we have to take him to Kadir.
你胡说什么? 咱们救了他 瞧他好好的
What are you talkin' about? We got him out, like you said. Come on.
我们宣誓联手去卡迪亚的
We swore an oath, Just-Joan and I. We go to Kadir.
你吃错药了
What is it with you?!
老天呀 凡事都得依你不成? 就像搭船的事?
Jesus! Everything's always gotta be your way? It's just like the goddamn boat!
你什么意思? 我可没说 要在你船上待半年的
What do you mean "my way"? It wasn't my idea to spend six months on your boat!
- 很好 吵得精彩 我喜欢听 - 好吧 我老实告诉你吧
- Oh, debate good. I enjoy. - OK, let me tell you what I put up with.
有次在金丝雀岛靠港 当时是半夜 正睡得熟
We're moored off the Canary Islands. Midnight, sound asleep.
突然闯来3个读者 说是要拿船锚当纪念品
Three crazed Joan Wilder fans decide they want the anchor of the Angelina for a souvenir!
- 害我们漂了好几天 另一个却... - 打到岔 轮到她了
- We were drifting for days! And the other... - Stop. I'm sorry. It's time for Just-Joan.
- 在科加索那一次呢? 杰克 - 得了吧你
- Remember the Costa del Sol, Jack? - Oh, come on!
说好跟我在州长家碰面的
He's gotta meet me at the governor's for dinner.
你却带了一批篮球队来
And you show up with the entire national basketball team!
他们肚子饿呀
They were hungry.
我正要说这件事 你从来不为我着想的
This is what I'm talking about. Sometimes you could think about me.
你甩了我跟奥马走 是为我着想吗?
Oh, I suppose you were thinking all about me when you took off with Omar?
- 可知道他炸了我的船吗? - 我们的船?
- He blew up my boat! - Our boat?
- 又变成我们的了 - 辩得真精彩 不分胜负
- Oh, now it's our boat? - Good debate. It's equal, no winners.
- 琼妮 快点走吧 - 等一下 他炸我们的船 是什么意思?
- Just-Joan, we must hurry. - Wait. He blew up our boat?
我搞不懂干嘛跟他瞎耗?
Why are you risking your life for this guy?
我做了承诺 不能食言呀
I made a commitment. I can't break it.
好哇 好得很
OK. Fine.
老实告诉你吧 我不是了你来的
But I'm gonna tell you the truth. I didn't come here for you anyway. No!
我有票大交易
I'm on to something big.
- 宝石 尼罗河宝石 - 跟我们走 我就是乔哈拉
- A jewel. The Jewel of the Nile. - Come with us. I am Jawhara!
- 他是指乔 - 谢啦 乔 心领了
- That means Joe. - Thanks, Joe, but no thanks.
我不能害她失信
I wouldn't want her to break her commitment.
杰克
Oh, Jack...
别这样嘛
Come on.
这一枪是为了吉琳号的
That's for the Angelina.
乔的帐还没算
I still owe you for Joan.
求求你 让我活着走吧
Oh, no. Oh, God. Please, let me get out of this alive.
我向上帝发誓 从今起做个乖宝宝
I swear to God I'll be a good boy from tomorrow on.
今晚我就要杀柯顿
But tonight I gotta kill Colton.
是琼妮怀德
Heydi Joan Wilder!
- 你怎么不把我的身份告诉他? - 我太了解他了
- Why you didn't tell your friend about me? - Oh, I know him.
他宁可为了参加派对 绝不会为了什么理想 千里跋涉来这
He'd go halfway round the world for a party. He wouldn't cross town for a noble cause.
- 人心隔肚皮呀 - 可不是 杰克本性难移呀
- People can surprise you. - No, he's just Jack. He'll never change.
就像...
Like a...
石头吧
Like a stone.
永远都是石头 手打开吧
It's always a stone. Open your hand.
有些改变是看不见的
Change is not always visible.
- 好吧 咱们联合吧 - 什么?
- Let's show some hustle! - What?
你的奥马朋友 他没有你活不下去
Your buddy Omar! What is it? He can't live without you?
- 要跑步? - 对 跑步
- Are we jogging? - We are jogging.
情况越来越好了
Greece is looking better and better.
要命
Oh, shit!
他干嘛一个劲地死缠不休
Just tell me why this guy wants you so bad.
- 乔 你去哪? - 这边来
- Hey, Joe, where you going? - This way.
- 开玩笑呀你 - 抄山路快一点
- You gotta be kidding. - He knows the mountains better than you.
你饶了我吧
Joan, will you give me a break?
美国凡事讲民主 表决吧
America - democracy. We vote, huh?
停!
Stop!
开火
Fire.
快走 走
Hurry up. Let's go!
趴下
Get down!
搞什么民主表决?
It's a black day for democracy.
- 放心吧 我不是死在山野的命 - 我们呢?
- Do not worry. It's not my destiny to die here. - What about us?
那又另当别论了
That's another ball game.
拉西
Rachid!
琼妮怀德
Joan Wilder!
我没有恶意
I wish no harm to you!
我是你朋友 是你朋友
I'm your friend! Your fan!
快投降吧
Please surrender!
你跟他结了什么仇了?
What did you do for this guy Omar you never did for me?
臭娘们
Bloody bitch!
小心
Oh, shit! Look out!
奥马 太差劲了
Hey, Omar! Eat rocks!
快走
Let's go.
我抓到棍子了
I got something.
奴比安族
Nubians.
我以为避得过他们呢
I was hoping to avoid them.
这儿老大是谁?
Sell any books here?
- 兄弟呀 兄弟 - 你乐个什么劲?
- Main man! Hey, my man! - What are you so happy about?
面带笑容 这一幕可以上国家地理杂志
Just keep smiling. Maybe they'll think we're from National Geographic.
你好啊
Hey! How ya doin'?
他说我们翻山越岭来这
He says it's many days' long trip over high mountains.
希望我们一路愉快
And he wishes us a very pleasant journey.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢大家 后会有期了
All right. Thank you, guys. Catch you next time. Goodbye.
杰克
Come on, Jack.
杰克先生 琼妮怀德 酋长说要赐福 你们的婚姻和孩子
Ah, Mr Jack! Just-Joan! The Chief's son, he wishes to make a blessing for your marriage.
我们没结婚
We're not married.
他说既然你没结婚 他儿子想向你求婚
He says, because you are not married, that his son wishes to court you.
- 这... - 噢 那个...
- Oh, I just... - Oh, no, that's...
实在太好了 不过 这位女士和我一起的
That's very nice, but the lady is... She's with me.
他说既然两男追一个 就得比武决定
He says that because there is more than one suitor, that you must wrestle his son.
和他儿子比武
I gotta wrestle his son?
你好啊?
How ya doin'?
放心 这小家伙好对付
OK. This one I think I can handle.
好吧
OK!
不是?
No?
侯赛因
Hussein!
各位 有话好商量呀
Wait a minute, guys. Let's talk this over like gentlemen!
好 你和我 你和我 好吗?
All right. You guys are with me, huh?
我 好吧
Yeah, me. All right.
帮个忙 说我们同居半年了 狗屎
Do me a favour. Tell him we lived together for six months. Shit.
好吧 开始吧
All right, what are the rules?
好吧
Right.
不要 放下我...
I'm sorry about that.
别扔左边 不要
No, not the left one! No!
杰克
Jack.
不入虎穴焉得虎子
No pain, no gain.
不要
Let me go!
- 不 - 我们玩过这一套吗?
- No! - Can we talk about this?
别打了
Stop it!
快想办法呀你
We have to do something!
我在想了
I am doing something.
乔 他....
Joe, he's...
他赢了
He wins.
杰克
Jack.
- 你真棒 - 差点被他打死
- That was great! - Great, huh? I could've gotten killed!
这个部落中 女人选男人
This is the marriage dance. In this tribe, the women, they choose the man.
再根据习俗 他们要相守一辈子
And then, according to the custom, they will be together for life.
跳个舞就定终生?
They get all that from one dance?
我觉得好美
It's beautiful!
你想加入我们 就把鞋袜脱掉
Ralph, if you want to be one of us, take off your shoes and socks.
想加入我们 就得用心眼看
If you want to be one of us, you must see with the eyes of your heart,
- 不是用肉眼看 - 我明白了
- not with the eyes of your head. - Gotcha, yeah.
心不会感觉到痛的 只要你懂我们的方法
Your heart will never give you fear or pain if you know our way.
不了 谢谢你 兄弟 宝石你还是留着吧
No, thanks, pal. Keep your friggin' jewel.
- 不要 - 你害怕了吗?
- No! - Are you afraid?
我只想保住我的脚
I just had my feet resoled.
- 你期望最不幸的事是什么? - 自己会变成一只鸡
- What is the worst that can happen to you? - I could wind up a Chicken McNugget.
- 最幸运的又是什么? - 安度这个危机找到宝石
- What is the best that could happen to you? - I could get through this and find the Jewel.
这就是你的选择?
It's your choice.
看下面
Look down.
烫呀 烫木碳
Hot coals!
我成功了 成功了 我是你们的一员了
I did it! I did it! I'm one of us!
好 棒
All right! Yeah!
你的害怕是愚蠢而不智的
Your fears - they make you foolish.
去找她 杰克
Go to her, Jack.
- 对不起 我又害你跟人打架了 - 开玩笑
- I'm sorry I got people shooting at you again. - You kidding?
我们是天造地设的一对
We're the perfect couple when we got people shooting at us.
- 良宵苦短 不宜多说 - 大概是我期望太多了
- Just the slow times I'm not too good at. - I guess I just expect too much.
我们废话太多
Maybe we both expect too much.
天呀
Oh, boy.
谢谢你来这陪我
Thank you for coming to Kadir with me.
这个村庄是拜了尼罗河之赐
This valley is gift of the Nile.
我离开这太久了
I've been away from here too long.
我越来越喜欢这小子了
You know, I'm getting to like this guy Joe. He's growing on me.
找到宝石分他一份如何?
What do you say we cut him in on this jewel, if we ever find it?
杰克
Jack...
我们找到宝石了
We have the Jewel.
你说什么? 在哪呀?
What are you talking about? Where?
那儿
Well, there.
- 宝石在乔手上? - 不对
- What, Joe's got the Jewel? - No.
他就是宝石
Joe is the Jewel.
乔是尼罗河的宝石?
Joe is the Jewel of the Nile?
他是个圣人 "尼罗河的宝石"是他的宗教头衔
He's a holy man. That's his religious title.
乔就是宝石?
Joe is the Jewel.
你为什么不早告诉我? 干嘛瞒着我?
Why didn't you tell me the truth? Why'd you keep it from me?
我担心你知道了就不会来了
Because I thought if you knew, you wouldn't come with us.
或许会给你个惊喜
Maybe I would've surprised you.
再做第二次傻瓜
I think I've come through once or twice, if I remember right.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你说得对 你一向都会来的
You're right. You come through all the time.
可笑
It's funny.
我一直以为还有机会的
I really thought we had a chance.
看呀 去卡迪亚的车子
Look! The train to Kadir!
快呀 杰克 今晚之前就可以到了
Come on, Jack. Inshallah, we'll be there tonight.
- 人都去哪了? - 他们去朝圣 参观卡迪亚大典
- What a lot of people! - They are going to see the false redeemer.
- 又是奥马搞的? - 到时就知道了
- Omar again, huh? - We'll see about that.
糟了
Shit!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
快呀
Come on!
跳呀
Jump!
不
No!
杰克
Jack.
撑住 琼妮
No! Hang on, Joan!
杰克 小心
Jack, watch out!
有人...
It's...
快呀 加油 快跑
Guys, wait up! Come on, Humphrey. Go, go, go!
想办法呀
Do something!
我能怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
柯顿
Colton!
大骗子 你给我解释 我要知道怎么回事
Your ass is grass, and I'm a lawn mower, Colton!
柯顿 你逃不了的 我不会放过你的
Colton, I'll get you! Colton, I'm on to ya!
柯顿
Colton.
好哇
Yeah.
太好了 咱们走
All right, yeah!
好了 我们走 快离开这儿
All right! Let's go, come on. Let's get out of here!
琼妮 你真行
Just-Joan, you're gre...
欢迎 欢迎
Welcome.
平常我是不搭火车的 不幸直升机出了点意外
I don't usually travel by train, but I had a small accident with my helicopter.
但愿我们及时赶到卡迪亚
May we reach Kadir in time.
进去以后 就得找到去卡迪亚的入口
Once we get inside, we must find the entrance to the catacombs.
最好的T恤 5披索
T-shirts! Buy T-shirts!
快滚 T恤给我 我买 行了吧? 快滚
Gimme the T-shirt. I'll buy it, I'll buy it. Get outta here, will ya?
我佩服两位对彼此的忠贞不二
You know, I really admire your loyalty to each other.
我将给你们相守至死的机会
And I'm going to give you a chance to be together to the very end.
其实也不然
Well, not exactly.
一方先看对方死
One will watch the other die.
谁先呢?
But which one?
拉西
Rachid.
- 那是羊血吗? - 对
- Is that the goat's blood? - Yes.
老鼠最喜欢的
Very popular with the inhabitants of these catacombs.
- 老鼠 - 它们会吃到一滴不剩
- Rats. - Yes. They eat until they get the last drop.
不过你放心 柯顿先生 你不会孤独死去
But don't worry, Mr Colton. You won't be alone.
拉西会在怀德小姐身上 浇硫酸腐蚀她
Rachid is now placing acid that will eat through Miss Wilder's rope.
这么做又何苦
What kind of sick pervert would go to this trouble?
- 干脆一枪毙了我们 - 杰克
- Why don't you shoot us?! - Jack!
想出这种手段 你真是丧心病狂呀
What kind of demented psychopath would even think of this?
- 这是个秘室 - 什么?
- The Savage Secret. - What?
我最畅销的书里
Was my biggest seller.
就当这是你最后一趟冒险吧 怀德小姐
Think about this pit as your last adventure, Joan Wilder.
百姓等着我呐
My people await me.
拉西 走
Rachid.
走吧
Come on.
你胡说什么? 我一向是和专家合作的
What you talkin' about? I work with professional people.
你转告他 有他没他 节目都要照做
You tell His Highness the show starts with him or without him.
想死的傻瓜大会串 想带个石头回国
Goddamn beanie convention. Wind up goin' home with a rug.
入口呀
The entrance!
打黄灯 开始
Give me a red to the yellow. And cue!
叫你打黄色灯呀
I said give me a red gel down there!
开始 拜托你开始呀
And cue! For Gawd's sake, cue!
慢一点 来点烟雾
Build it, build it softly. And give me some smoke.
很好 很好 非常好 现在把升降机慢慢升起来
That's good, that's good, that's very good. Now, bring it up slowly.
奥马
Omar.
房间和路太多了
There are many rooms and many ways.
你走这边
You! You go this way.
你走那边
And, you! You go this way.
我们呢 走这边
And we: We go this way.
这地方臭气薰人
Boy, it stinks in this place.
情况还不错 朋友
What looks good, amigo?
你朝那走 我走这边
You go from this way. And... I go this way.
好
All right.
逗逼
What a fruit loop.
- 他们怎么走出密室的? - 什么?
- How'd they get out? - What?
他们是怎么走出恐怖密室的?
In The Savage Secret, how'd they get out?
杰西的靴子里藏了一把刀
Jesse had a knife hidden in his boot.
你身上没带刀吧?
You wouldn't happen to have a knife, would ya?
- 我连内裤都没穿 - 好
- I'm not even wearing underwear. - Great!
不要
No!
我们是很好的搭档对吧?
We were good together, weren't we, Joan Wilder?
最好的
The best.
- 我们会成功的 - 对
- And we're gonna make it. - Yeah.
我爱你 姑娘
Oh, God. I love you, lady.
我爱你 杰克
I love you, Jack.
你愿意嫁我吗?
Will you marry me?
- 我愿意 - 我不准你再离开我了
- Yes! - Because I never want you leaving me again.
你这么说不是因为快死了吧?
You're not just saying that because this is it, are you?
我是因为不怕说实话了
I'm saying it because I'm not afraid to say it any more.
你想去哪度蜜月?
So where do you wanna go on our honeymoon?
奥马
Omar.
快滚 死老鼠 快滚
Rats! Get out of here, you... Goddamn rat farm! Go on!
- 洛夫 洛夫 快救我们呀 - 你们也有今天呀
- Ralph! Get us out of here, will ya? - Ah! And there's the biggest rat of all.
柯顿 瞧瞧你
Colton, look at you. You...
你可知道我梦想这一天 有多少次了
You don't know how many nights I dreamed of this.
- 只差你在梦中是血肉模糊 - 拜托放下我们
- Except your flesh was torn off your body. - Ralph, please, just help us down.
杰克
Jack! Hold on!
想不到吧? 杰克
Well, well, well, Colton.
这笔交易可以重新谈判了 是不是呀? 泰山
I think this calls for a renegotiation. Don't you, Tarzan? Huh?
倒像是1730年的情形
This looks a little bit more like 70-30.
- 或者是1820年 - 洛夫 先把老鼠赶走
- Or maybe even 80-20. - Ralph, will ya get the rats off that rope?!
- 我不敢碰老鼠的 - 别害怕
- I don't go near rats, buddy. - Ralph, do not be afraid.
谨记一个方法 用你的心眼去看
Remember the Sufi way: See with your heart.
我看到的还是老鼠 别听他胡扯
My heart sees rats, Pop. Don't let this garb fool you.
说吧 柯顿 宝石在哪?
Come on, Colton. Where's the Jewel?
洛夫 我就是宝石 尼罗河宝石
Ralph, I am the Jewel. The Jewel of the Nile.
我还是皇后呐 你安静点
And I'm a kumquat from Queens. Pipe down, towel-head!
- 快点 洛夫 - 快会东西盖住洞口
- Come on, Ralph. - Take the ladder and put it over the well.
- 求求你 别让我们死 - 这是个好主意
- Please, don't let us die! - That's a good idea, Legs.
我不会让你们死的 除非你们先说出宝石的下落
I ain't gonna let you die, but I ain't movin' no ladder until you come across with the rock!
这下子又回到 1910年了 矮冬瓜
Lookin' more like 90-10! Huh, kumquat?
- 放我下来 兄弟 - 杰克 帮我替宝石松绑
- Did you get the ladder all right? - Jack, help me unlock the Jewel.
宝石? 这么说真的是他?
The Jewel? You mean you weren't shittin' me? That guy really is the Jewel?
快点 还来得及阻止奥马 快走
Come on. We still got time to stop Omar. Let's go.
奥马 自作孽不可活
Ralph, that is not the Sufi way.
我不知道怎么回事 每次碰上他 就把我逼得快发疯了
I don't know what got into me, Jewels. Every time I'm around this guy he makes me crazy.
快点 放我下来 宝石 快点吧
Come on. Tell him to cut me down, Jewels. Come on, huh?
奥马
Omar.
别动开关 臭女人
Don't fuck around with the equipment! Bloody woman!
他们来了 杰克
Here they come, Jack.
我的天 瞧瞧吧 简直像是小学操场
Oh, my God. Look at this. Looks like Our Lady of Mount Palmer schoolyard.
等一下
Hold it!
对不起 让一让 让个路
Excuse me. Pardon me. Coming through.
你好吗?
Oh, Rachid.
什么事可以好好谈
How ya doin'? Let's talk this over before you butcher me alive.
你干嘛板着脸呐
What are you getting so steamed about?
瞧吧 管用了
Look at that. It worked!
看! 乔哈拉呀
Look, Jawhara!
乔哈拉
Al-Jawhara.
快上墙 快
Get over the wall. Come on!
跑
Get goin'.
继续跑
Keep going.
早知道咱们是冤家路窄 快抓呀
I knew we'd hook up again, Colton. Get it?
我向上帝发誓
I swear to God!
我发誓
My right hand to God!
快呀
Come on!
我就快死了 奥马的一切全泡汤了
I am dead, Miss Wilder. All that will be written for Omar is an epitaph.
不过死也拖你一起
But I will not be alone.
谁再来救你?
Who is going to save you now?
谁?
Who?
你的题材有了吧?
Well, you got your story.
还有更好的呢
I got a lot more than that.
你们结婚了
You are married!
我还是一样的下场
Always a bridesmaid, never the bride.
到头来两手空空
As usual, it's zilch for poor Ralphie.
你的
You are Sufi.
收着吧
Keep it always.
伙计们
Guys!
太棒了
Sufis rule!